# Jinhyuk Yoon

#### **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Rooms 011, Science Building 4, 77 Cheongam-Ro, Nam-Gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I'm a science communicator, interaction designer, and engineer building interactive experience through tactile manipulation. I'm interested in a tactile interface which would bridge between the world of digital and analog to bring a new paradigm of education. To broaden an insight for education, I've been participating in various projects such as start-up business, talk, performance, volunteer and art work. With deep interests in technology and education, I have been trying to create meaningful experience.

# **Professional Experience**

Geekble Mar 2019 – Present

**Communications Manager** 

Creating attractive video contents to deliver science knowledge in new media platform.

# **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Feb 2019 - Present

Research Intern

Developing a pneumatic haptic device to provide interactive tactile experiences.

# Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab

Jan 2019 – Feb 2019

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyzed mechanical property of spring and damper hinge mounted in oven door. Deployed the analysis result on interactive data platform to simplify design process.

**Sovoro** Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

**Communications Manager** 

Conducted UI/UX research and design of the service, catalog design, and market research. Engaged in business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

#### **Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity**

May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed science street performance, and staged science play only for adult as a finalist of the FameLab Korea and a science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

#### **Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center**

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

# **Leadership Experience**

## **POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering**

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

#### **POSTECH, Student Election Committee**

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

## **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering**

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Minor in Industrial Management Engineering.

Expect to graduate with Magna Cum Laude.

# **Awards and Honors**

Commission Letter  Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator	2016
<b>Finalist</b> Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 <sup>rd</sup> FameLab Korea	2016
<b>Runners Up</b> Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council	2017
Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH	2015
Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering	2015, 2016

## **National Academic Excellence Scholarship**

2016 - Present

2016

Korea Student Aid Foundation

The 2<sup>nd</sup> POSTECH Hackathon

The 4th Prize

# **KT&G Foundation Scholarship**

**POSTECH** 

### **Jigok Scholarship**

**POSTECH** 

2014 - 2016

2016

# **Selected Talks**

Keynote Speech, "About Experience", POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang	2018
Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon	2016
Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju	2016
Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu	2018
Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul	2017
Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon	2016
Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji High School, Yongin	2017
Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan	2017
Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan	2017

# **Publications**

### To My Students, To My Teachers

Andrea Sohn and Jinhyuk Yoon, The Korea Fulbright Infusion, Vol 6, 2013, 39 – 41.

### **TEDxPOSTECH Brightened by Passion**

Jinhyuk Yoon, POSTECHIAN, Winter, 2015, 34 – 35.

#### **About Mechanical Engineering**

Jinhyuk Yoon, POSTECHIAN, Spring, 2016, 30 – 31.

# **Skills and Tools**

### **Programming Language**

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

## **Graphic Design**

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

## **3D Design & Analysis**

Solidworks, NX